UK

Data Privacy Statement
======================

**I. General**

Thank you for your interest in upday! We need some information about you in order to offer the upday app. At upday, we take the protection of your personal data very seriously and we’ll always process your data in line with the applicable regulations for data protection, in particular the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). With this data privacy statement, we intend to fully inform you on the nature, size, and purpose of the personal data we process, and your rights as the person concerned.

**1\. Data Controller**

Your data is processed by upday GmbH & Co. KG,  Axel-Springer-Str. 65, 10888 Berlin, Germany, phone: +49 30 2591 0, email: [\[email protected\]](https://www.upday.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) and Data Controller as per the GDPR, hereafter also referred to as “we” or “us”.

When we mention "upday" in this document, we are referring to: [www.upday.com](https://www.upday.com/) and the various sub-domains, including those from different countries, the upday app including all subpages, content, and features available on these platforms. Several parts of upday are also referred to as “news service”. This also applies when we mention the website or the app.

Our services are intended for the general public and not for children. We do not knowingly collect any personal data from users who are classified as children by national legislature.

**2\. Contact Information**

Please contact our data protection officer at any time with questions and suggestions regarding data protection as well as to enforce your rights as a data subject:

upday GmbH & Co. KG

Axel Springer St. 65

10888 Berlin

[\[email protected\]](https://www.upday.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Insofar as data processing is carried out with a joint controller pursuant to Art. 26 GDPR, both controllers act as a joint contact point.

**3\. Launching the website / app**

When you use our offer, we automatically set necessary cookies and collect and process the following information to enable the usability of the functions provided and to ensure the security and stability of our offer:

\- Information about the accessing end device and the operating system version used

\- Date and time of access

\- IP address

\- Cookies and pseudonymous IDs

\- Websites from which the user accesses our website or which the user accesses via our website

The processing of your IP address is necessary to enable the delivery of our offer to your end device and to measure the efficiency and technical performance of our offer. The legal basis for the data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR.

Our servers also store your IP address for up to 14 days for the purpose and in the interest of being able to guarantee the security of our offer (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR). We also process your shortened IP address for the purpose and in the interest of being able to prevent the insertion of harmful programs via the displayed advertising. The legal basis for this is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR.

If you download our app from an app store of a third-party provider (such as iTunes, Google, etc.) and Axel Springer SE becomes your contractual partner for the acquisition of the app in accordance with the applicable terms of use of such a provider, we process the data provided to us by the third-party provider in order to enable you to use the app. The legal basis for the data processing is Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPR.

**4\. Data Processing Location**

We also process data in countries outside of the European Economic Area, for example in the USA. To ensure that a suitable level of data protection is observed, we make use of the EU Standard Contractual Clauses for the preparation of the contracts with services employed in Third Countries as per Art. 46 para. 2 point c  GDPR, unless there is an adequacy decision issued by the European Commission for that Third Country:

**5\. Storage Duration**

We process personal data only as long as this is necessary for the respective purpose stated in this data protection declaration. The personal data will then be deleted, provided that no legal retention periods conflict with data deletion.

**6\. Data Transfer**

Unless otherwise stated in this privacy policy, we will only transfer your personal data to third parties if the transfer is necessary to fulfill our contractual obligations to you and this is obviously done with or together with another provider, we are otherwise legally entitled or obligated to transfer, or you have given us your consent to do so.

**II. Your rights as a data subject**

**1\. Access, Rectification, Erasure, Restriction and the Right to be Forgotten**

You can obtain information from us at any time and free of charge as to whether personal data relating to you is being processed by us and specifically what data is being stored about you, as well as request a copy of the stored data. You can also have incorrect data corrected and completed. You can also request the deletion and restriction of your personal data.

In order to receive information or to delete your data, we ask you to contact our customer support team via the upday mobile app, alternatively send an email to [\[email protected\]](https://www.upday.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) where our team will inform you of the steps you need to take.

**2\. Data Portability**

Where applicable, you also have the right to have the personal data concerning you transferred to you or to another controller in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, provided that the processing is based on consent or a contract and is carried out by automated means. However, this does not apply if the processing is not necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller. You also have the right to obtain the direct transfer of personal data from one controller to another controller where technically feasible and where this does not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

**3\. Revocation & Objection**

You can revoke your consent to upday with tracking and cookies at any time via "[Privacy Settings](#)" at the bottom of each page on upday.com. Otherwise, you can revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future at the above-mentioned contact address.

In case we process personal data for direct marketing purposes, you will have the right to object at any time to the processing of your personal data for such marketing by contacting the abovementioned address.

Furthermore, you have the right to object at any time, on grounds relating to your particular situation, to the processing of personal data concerning you which is carried out on the basis of a legitimate or public interest. We will no longer process the personal data in the event of the objection, unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing serves to assert, exercise or defend legal claims.

If we are processing personal data for the purpose of direct marketing, you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data at any time for the purpose of such marketing by contacting the aforementioned address. This also applies to profiling insofar as it is connected with such direct marketing. You also have the right to file an objection for reasons arising from your particular circumstances against processing of your personal data that we are engaged in for scientific, historical research or statistical purposes, unless such processing is required to perform a task that is in the public interest.

**4\. Right of Complaint**

Furthermore, you have the right to legal remedy from your supervising authority as well as the possibility to lodge a complaint. The supervision authority with which the complaint has been lodged, shall inform the complainant on the progress and the outcome of the complaint including the possibility of legal remedy.

**5\. Automated Decision Making**

We do not use automatic decision-making or profiling in the sense of Art. 22 GDPR.

**III. Use of upday news services with tracking and cookies**

**1\. General**

If you consent to the use of upday with tracking and cookies, not only our own content or content that is played out on our behalf (Art. 28 GDPR) will be displayed, but also content from third parties. This can be editorial content, recommendations for external content, games and surveys, but also product advertising, e.g. in the form of personalized, i.e. on your presumed interests based on your usage behavior selected advertising banners on the side of the page or ads under articles. The legal basis for the processing of personal data is in each case Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.

If such content is loaded, this is done from servers of the respective third-party providers. This always involves the transmission of certain data to the third-party providers, in many cases also personal data. In addition, cookies or similar technologies are used for most of the services of the third-party providers by means of which the content is loaded. The purposes for which this data is processed by the third-party providers on their own responsibility, but also partly on our responsibility, are manifold.

Here we inform you about the use of cookies or comparable technologies and the processing of personal data by the third-party providers.

**2\. Cookies and Similar Technologies**

In order to provide our service, ensure security, prevent fraud, eliminate errors and provide content, the use of cookies and similar technologies is necessary (essential). Your [Privacy Settings](#) and your cookie settings (regarding permitted/blocked cookies) are also stored on your end device. The use of cookies is required for us to provide you with the service requested by you. Please refer to the [Privacy Setting](#) for further information on these special categories of cookies.

Cookies are small files that your browser places in a folder designated for this purpose on your device. This makes it possible, for instance, to determine whether you have visited a website before. Many cookies contain what is known as a “cookie ID”. A cookie ID is a unique cookie identifier. It consists of a string of characters which websites and servers can associate with the specific web browser where the cookie has been stored. This enables visited websites and servers to differentiate between the specific browser of the Data Subject and other web browsers containing different cookies. A specific web browser can be recognised and identified using the unique cookie ID. Without additional information, cookies cannot be used to identify you personally. Cookies and similar technologies are needed to (partly) collect personal data or to store it on your terminal device and to subsequently process personal data, among other purposes:

\- to select simple displays,

\- Create a personalized ad profile,

\- select personalized ads,

\- Create a personalized content profile

\- select personalized content,

\- Measure ad performance,

\- Measure content performance,

\- use market research to gain insights into target groups, and

\- to develop and improve products,

(so-called "IAB processing purposes").

For more information on IAB processing purposes and individual third party providers, please read further in the [Privacy Settings](#).

When using apps, technology that is functionally equivalent to cookies is used instead of cookies; this may be for example the operating system-specific advertising ID, vendor ID or a randomly generated user ID.

Unless otherwise agreed, we and our partners will only employ other cookies and similar technologies with your consent expressed through the [Privacy Setting](#). These cookies are used by us and our partners to store and process data on your end device for the purposes listed below in this Privacy Policy. If consent is not granted for the setting of cookies, it may not be possible to fully use all functions of our website.

More information on the cookies used and equivalent technologies and our partners is provided in the relevant parts of this Privacy Policy and your [Privacy Setting](#), where you can withdrawal your consent with future effect at any time. Previously created cookies can also be deleted by you at any time using your web browser or another software solution. This is possible in all standard web browsers. Please note that this will also delete any settings you have made in your [Privacy Setting](#), such that these will need to be reconfigured when you visit our website again. The duration of the cookies is limited to a maximum of one year unless otherwise stated.

**3\. Geo Location**

For the purpose and in the interest of displaying content with a regional reference to your location, we process your IP address. The geographical information obtained in this way can in no way be used to draw conclusions about the specific location of a user. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR.

**4\. Affiliate Marketing**

If you access our website from an external website via an advertising banner, we will receive information from the operator of the external website (“Affiliate”) that a user has accessed our service via that external website. This information is stored by us in a cookie on your end device.

Clicking on an advertising banner of an external service provider on our website (“Advertiser”) will forward you to the relevant site of the Advertiser. In this case, we as the Affiliate will transmit the information to the Advertiser that a user has accessed their website from our website. This information is the product ID associated with the marketed service and the identification number assigned to us (Affiliate ID) as well as a user ID comprising a series of arbitrary numbers. This information is usually stored by the Advertiser in a cookie on your end device and is automatically deleted after no later than 30 days. If you submit an order on the Advertiser’s website within 30 days, this information will automatically be transmitted in encrypted form to us upon conclusion of the order process. We can only learn from the information that a user has accessed the Advertiser’s external website from our website via the advertising banner and that they have purchased the marketed product there. No personal data is processed in this connection. Please refer to the Privacy Policy of the Advertiser on their website for information about how the Advertiser processes personal data.

In service of our interest in and for the purpose of optimising the advertising of third parties (“Advertisers”) on our website and the advertising that we place on third-party websites (“Affiliates”), we make use of the services of “Affiliate Networks”, for which a cookie will be stored on your system. This cookie stores the Affiliate ID, the User ID and the Product ID. The purpose of storing this data is to process commission payments between the Advertiser and Affiliate via the Affiliate Network. You can prevent cookies from being set by our website at any time, as explained above, by configuring the web browser in use to block cookies; this represents your permanent objection to the setting of cookies. Further information on the individual affiliate networks and your rights as a data subject can be found in their respective privacy policies.

**5\. Partner Offers and Services**

If you have given your consent to upday with tracking and cookies, we also integrate interesting offers and services from selected partners ("partner offers") into our website. The partner service page is provided by the partner indicated there. The partner is responsible for the content of the partner service page and the data processing operations taking place there in accordance with Art. 4 No. 7 GDPR. Information about the Partner can be found in the Partner's imprint. For information on the data processing operations that take place via the partner service page and your rights as a data subject, please refer to the partner's privacy policy, which is also linked there.

**IV. Social media and partner offers**

**1\. Facebook Fanpages**

We use Facebook Fanpages under the following links, for which we are jointly responsible with Meta Platforms Ireland Limited:

In joint responsibility with Facebook, we analyse how you use our Fanpage (Page Insights). You can obtain the information required by the GDPR on data processing within the scope of Page Insights from Facebook; currently by name in Facebook's privacy policy at [https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/information\_about\_page\_insights\_data.](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/information_about_page_insights_data)

Facebook also provides you with the relevant contents of the joint responsibility processing agreement concluded between Facebook and us in accordance with Art. 26 GDPR; currently at the following link: [https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/page\_controller\_addendum](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/page_controller_addendum). You may exercise your right of appeal to any supervisory authority having jurisdiction over you and seek redress there.

**According to the GDPR, you have a right to** [**object**](https://www.facebook.com/help/contact/1638046109617856) **to the processing of your data. You can learn more about this and other data subject rights in the Facebook privacy notices linked above.**

For Page Insights on our Facebook Fanpages, Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland acts as the common point of contact and processes all requests to exercise data subject rights.

As part of the Page Insights, we ourselves only receive anonymised statistics - we do not have access to personal data processed by Facebook. The processing of anonymised data by us is based on legal regulations that allow us to process personal data because we have an overriding legitimate interest in gaining a better understanding of the interests of visitors to our Fanpage (Art. 6 (1) f) GDPR). Facebook offers various community functions on the fan pages with which you can interact with other users, for example by posting articles there, leaving comments or liking or sharing articles. Please note that these areas are publicly accessible and that any personal information you post or provide when registering may be viewed by others. We cannot control how other users of the Fanpages use this information. In particular, we cannot prevent unsolicited messages from being sent to you.

**2\. Social Plugins**

There are no social media plugins integrated on this website that directly load data from the servers of the relevant social media providers. The integrated "plugins" are rather simple links to the relevant third-party sites, which we illustrate with corresponding graphics. A transmission of personal data to the operator of the social media service through the known plugins therefore does not take place.

**3\. Contextual contents**

In certain areas of our website you will find content and advertising selected and displayed by Outbrain UK Limited, 100 New Bridge Street, London, EC4V 6JA, United Kingdom ("Outbrain"). This selection of content and advertising is based exclusively on non-personal elements such as the content of the relevant page of our site (contextual) or on which topics or pages in our site are currently in particularly high demand. However, to establish the connection of your terminal device to the Outbrain server for the delivery of the relevant content and advertising, the processing of the IP address assigned to your terminal device at the relevant time by Outbrain is necessary. The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR.

We have entered into an agreement with Outbrain in accordance with Article 26 of the GDPR to ensure that your rights in relation to your personal data are protected. This agreement essentially stipulates that

* Outbrain will only process the IP address to establish the connection for serving content and advertising without your consent;
* the setting of cookies and other data processing will only take place if you have consented to the use of the upday news service with tracking and cookies;
* a data transfer to the USA may only take place subject to the relevant EU standard contractual clauses;
* we provide you with the information listed above;
* You can exercise requests in accordance with Art. 12 and 15-22 of the GDPR directly with Outbrain ([here](https://my.outbrain.com/recommendations-settings/home), see also Outbrain's [Privacy Policy](https://www.outbrain.com/privacy/)), but that if you wish to exercise your rights directly with us, Outbrain will assist us with the relevant information, etc.

For more information about Outbrain and your rights as a data subject against Outbrain, please refer to Outbrain's [privacy policy](https://www.outbrain.com/privacy/). Information on the data processing carried out by Outbrain and its purposes, if you have consented to the use of upday with tracking and cookies, can be found in the privacy policy.

**4\. Displaying third-party content (social networks, videos)**

If you have given your consent to use upday with tracking and cookies, you are also viewing services of the providers listed below, who are each responsible for data processing in accordance with Art. 4 No. 7 GDPR. Your browser establishes a direct connection to the server of the respective provider. In doing so, the provider always processes your IP address, which is necessary for establishing the connection to the provider's server and playing out the content. In this context, usage profiles (based on cookie IDs, among other things) may also be formed and enriched, including outside the European Economic Area. The legal basis for the data processing is in each case Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a, 49 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. You may grant or withdraw your consent at any time via through the [Privacy Settings](#). Further information on the processing of personal data by these providers and your rights as a data subject can be found in the privacy policy of the respective provider.

**\- Giphy** (Giphy, Inc., 416 W 13th Street Suite 207, New York, NY 10014)  

**\- Instagram** (Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland) [https://www.instagram.com/legal/privacy/](https://www.instagram.com/legal/privacy/)

\- **LinkedIn** (Ireland Unlimited Company, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland) [https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)

**\- Snapchat** (Snap Inc. 2772 Donald Douglas, Loop North Santa Monica, CA 90405 United States USA) [https://snap.com/en-US/privacy/privacy-policy](https://snap.com/en-US/privacy/privacy-policy)

**\- Twitter** (Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA), [https://twitter.com/en/privacy](https://twitter.com/en/privacy)

**\- YouTube** (Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland), [https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7671399?p=privacy\_guidelines&hl=de&visit\_id=0-636644030056539000-341535836&rd=1](https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7671399?p=privacy_guidelines&hl=de&visit_id=0-636644030056539000-341535836&rd=1)

We are jointly responsible with Facebook for the information collected via Facebook Business Tools of Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland ("Facebook"). Information about Facebook and the contact details of its data protection officer, as well as further information about how Facebook processes personal data, including the legal basis and how you can exercise your rights as a data subject against Facebook, can be found in Facebook's [data policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy). We have entered into a Joint Responsibility Agreement (Article 26 GDPR) with Facebook, which sets out our respective responsibilities for fulfilling our obligations under the GDPR with respect to joint processing. Thereafter, we are required to provide the above information and Facebook has assumed responsibility for the other data subject rights under Art. 15-20 of the GDPR.

**V Special services**

**1\. Social Login Integration**

We offer the possibility to log in to our service using social login integration. Your use of a certain social login is subject to the provider’s privacy policy, which can be found below. When using this integration option, you will be redirected to the given providers website where you will be required to give your access data, unless you are already logged in, in which case this step is skipped. We do not receive any access data.

Some of the information we may receive when you log in using social login platforms includes name, username (account URL), user ID, email, location, profile picture, gender, networks. Conversely, data may also be transferred from us to the respective social media platform. If you register with us via these social logins, then we store and process your data transferred to us for the purpose of registration.

Finally, to register with our login service, we need the email address that is stored on Facebook so that we can contact you independently of Facebook and create an account with us. If you agree that we use your Facebook data for the use of the respective service, as it is displayed on Facebook or explained above, you establish the connection in the social network between the network profile and the online service in the network and are then redirected back to the registration with us and the respective service that you just want to use. Please note that the step "Connect to the online service in the network" is skipped if you are already connected to the respective application on Facebook within the social network. We have now taken over the data provided by Facebook during the registration process and created an account for you. In the future, you can always log in to our services via the "Login with Facebook" button. The legal basis for the data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.

**\- Facebook** (Facebook Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland), [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info)

**\- Google** (Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland), [https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/10130420](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/10130420)

**2\. Your Contact Information**

When you contact us via one of our contact forms or by e-mail, the data you provide (your e-mail address, name and telephone number (if applicable) will be processed by us in order to process your inquiry and, if necessary, to contact you. We delete the data accruing in this context when it is no longer required for the aforementioned purpose, provided that the deletion does not conflict with any statutory retention obligations. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 lit. f GDPR. If you provide us with personal data of another person, you must take the necessary data protection measures beforehand, e.g. obtain the required prior consent of this person and inform him/her of the purpose for which you are providing the data to us.

**Status:** 20.09.2022
